Joseph Priestley Papers 1771-1803 Mss.B.P931 Mss.B.P931
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 21, 1799; 8" x 9 3/4"; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    Northumberland, A.L.S. 3p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan,no.38) Glasses and other instruments for scientific experiments; damages in transportation. Mr. Vaughan's difficulties. Printed in part: APS Library Bulletin for 1946, p.79.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 11, 1799; 8" x 9 3/4"; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    Northumberland, A.L.S. 3p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan,no.39) Is glad that Mr. Vaughan's affairs are better. Order for gold, silver, and platinum for experiments. Mentions Mr. Cooper.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Dec. 12, 1799; 8" x 13"; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    Northumberland, A.L.S. 2p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan,no.40) Finances. Comments on "Porcupine."
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 7, 1800; 8" x 13"; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    Northumberland, A.L.S. 1p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan,no.41) Encloses parcels for various persons. Arrival of his son, Joseph.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 21, 1801; 13-1/2x8-1/4; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    North[umberland], A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning Woodhouse. Thought he would have received a package of books.
  - Letter to the Rev. Mr. [Theophilus] Lindsey, Dec. 19, 1801; 7 3/4" x 12 3/4"; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    Northumberland, A.L.S. 4p., add. Seal. (see his Letters to various persons,no.51) Rejoices at return of peace; American politics. His health. Slowness of receiving books from England.
  - Letter to [Thomas Belsham], March 16, 1803; 11x8-1/2; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    Philadelphia, Typed L. 1p. Copy. (see Priestley papers.) Orders books for A.P.S.as John Vaughan requested. For request,see J.Vaughan to Priestley; March 8,1803 (in APS.Jounral...Corres.Sec. 1789-1823,p.41) Presented by E.F.Belding;10/11/62.
  - Letter to the Rev. Mr. [Theophilus] Lindsey, Aug. 27, 1803; 7 3/4" x 12 1/4"; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    North[umberlan]d, A.L.S. 4p., add. (see his Letters to various persons,no.52) The war and European politics. His health; his writings. Contains also a copy of Priestley's bookplate.
  - [Notes on the eulogium on Joseph Priestley to be delivered before the American philosophical society], [1804]; B P931b; 1.0 Volume(s); Barton, Benjamin Smith, 1766-1815 (Volume 1)
    [6p.] Photostat of manuscript. See Early minutes of the Society under dates of Feb. 17, 24, 1804. These notes were found by Mrs. J. R. Delafield among a group of Barton's papers in her possession. The photostat was presented to the Society in January, 1938.
- B P931.1 Photocopy Correspondence with John Wilkinson, 1789-1802; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
  Photostats of A.L.S's etc. 68 pieces. From originals in Municipal Library, Warrington, England. Table of contents with collection.